Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
Big liar
كاذب كبير
Shi Feifan is a big liar
شي فيفان كاذب كبير
Nan Batian
في باتيان
Wake up
استيقظ
Giving you a chance to redeem yourself
نمنحك فرصة لتصحيح أخطائك
Nan Batian
في باتيان
A clever way to leave no witnesses
طريقة ذكية لعدم ترك أي شهود
Lord Han
اللورد هان
The land has been sorted out
تم تسوية وضع الأرض
But it hasn't been allocated yet
لكن لم يتم تخصيصها بعد
If I leave just like this
إذا غادرت هكذا
Everything I've done before would be for nothing
كل ما فعلته من قبل سيكون بلا جدوى
Give me three more days
أعطني ثلاثة أيام أخرى
Just three days
ثلاثة أيام فقط
Alright, I promise you
حسناً، أعدك
That's great
هذا رائع
Don't fight, don't fight
لا تقاتل، لا تقاتل
There's enough for everyone
هناك ما يكفي للجميع
We have land now
لدينا أرض الآن
This is wonderful
هذا رائع
You ruin your own future
أنت تدمر مستقبلك بنفسك
Do you truly not regret it?
ألا تندم على ذلك حقاً؟
In one's lifetime
في حياة المرء
You must do a few things that make you proud
عليك أن تفعل بعض الأشياء التي تجعلك فخوراً بنفسك
Big, passionate things
أشياء عظيمة وعاطفية
The nation is its people
الأمة هي شعبها
The people are the nation
الشعب هو الأمة
So even if I face great danger
لذا حتى لو واجهت خطرًا كبيرًا
No matter the cost
بغض النظر عن التكلفة
I will still do it
سأفعل ذلك على أي حال
When I grow old one day
عندما أكبر في السن يوماً ما
Lying on a rocking chair
مستلقياً على كرسي هزاز
Looking back on my life
بالنظر إلى الوراء في حياتي
Only then will it all be worth it
عندها فقط سيكون كل شيء يستحق العناء
Truly meaningful
معنى حقيقي
Be an official like Shi Feifan
كن مسؤولاً مثل شي فيفان
I regret not meeting you earlier
أنا نادم على عدم لقائك في وقت سابق
It's not too late to know you now
لم يفت الأوان بعد للتعرف عليك الآن
Let's use tea instead of wine
لنستخدم الشاي بدلاً من النبيذ
I'll drink a cup with you
سأشرب معك كوبًا
Tea at midnight affects sleep
يؤثر شرب الشاي في منتصف الليل على النوم
Alright then
حسناً إذاً
When we reach the capital
عندما نصل إلى العاصمة
I'll have a good drink with you
سأشرب معك مشروباً جيداً
Alright
على ما يرام
It's finally done
لقد انتهى الأمر أخيراً
The three-day deadline is here
لقد حان الموعد النهائي الذي يمتد لثلاثة أيام
Lord Shi, it's time to go
يا سيد شي، حان وقت الرحيل
Even if I agree to go back with you
حتى لو وافقت على العودة معك
I might not make it back alive
قد لا أعود حياً
It's not that I don't trust you
ليس الأمر أنني لا أثق بك
But Nan Batian kills without warning
لكن نان باتيان يقتل دون سابق إنذار
The journey back may be dangerous
قد تكون رحلة العودة محفوفة بالمخاطر
Don't worry, Lord Shi
لا تقلق يا سيد شي
I'll risk my life to protect yours
سأخاطر بحياتي لحمايتك
Shi Feifan
شي فيفان
Do you have anything else to say?
هل لديك أي شيء آخر لتقوله؟
Your subject Shi Feifan has completed the resettlement
لقد أكملت شي فيفان، موضوعك، عملية إعادة التوطين
Today I return to report in the capital
أعود اليوم لأقدم تقريراً من العاصمة
Resettlement is complete
اكتملت عملية إعادة التوطين
You disregard the law
أنت تتجاهل القانون
You killed a prince
لقد قتلت أميراً
Is this your way of resettling?
هل هذه هي طريقتك في إعادة التوطين؟
Extraordinary times call for extraordinary actions
تتطلب الأوقات الاستثنائية إجراءات استثنائية
If I hadn't killed Liang Qing or divided the land
لو لم أقتل ليانغ تشينغ أو أقسم الأرض
The people would have rebelled soon
كان الشعب سيثور قريباً
Nonsense
هراء
Even with your silver tongue
حتى مع فصاحتك
You can't escape the fact you killed a court official
لا يمكنك الهروب من حقيقة أنك قتلت مسؤولاً قضائياً
If I don't kill the traitor
إذا لم أقتل الخائن
Should I let him keep harming the people?
هل أتركه يستمر في إيذاء الناس؟
You
أنت
Dying for the people
الموت من أجل الشعب
My life is worth it as Shi Feifan
حياتي تستحق أن أعيشها بشخصية شي فيفان
Shi Feifan
شي فيفان
Take a good look at yourself
ألقِ نظرة جيدة على نفسك
You're unbelievably bold
أنت جريء بشكل لا يصدق
Tyrant
طاغية
You
أنت
Insulting Your Majesty is a grave offense
إن إهانة جلالتكم جريمة خطيرة
You should be executed
يجب إعدامك
Your Majesty
جلالة الملك
For the merit he has earned
وذلك للجدارة التي اكتسبها
Please spare his life
أرجوكم ارحموا حياته
I, your old subject, will die for him
أنا، رعيتك القديمة، سأموت من أجله
Father
أب
Duke of Nan, you failed to teach your son
يا دوق نان، لقد فشلت في تعليم ابنك
Letting Shi Feifan cause a disaster
تسبب السماح لشي فيفان في كارثة
For your repeated military merits
تقديراً لجهودكم العسكرية المتكررة
Go home and reflect on your mistakes
عد إلى المنزل وفكر في أخطائك
Your Majesty
جلالة الملك
What did my father do wrong?
ما الخطأ الذي ارتكبه والدي؟
Your Majesty dares to act but not let me speak?
جلالتكم تجرؤون على التصرف ولا تدعوني أتكلم؟
Shielding the culprit is unjust
إن حماية الجاني أمر غير عادل
Letting the people suffer is unkind
إن ترك الناس يعانون هو أمر غير إنساني.
Now I have completed my task
لقد أنجزت مهمتي الآن
Yet Your Majesty wants to punish me
لكن جلالتكم تريدون معاقبتي
Believe it or not
صدق أو لا تصدق
History will judge for itself
سيحكم التاريخ على نفسه.
Fine, fine
حسنًا، حسنًا
You have a sharp tongue
لسانك سليط
Facing death, you still show no remorse
وأنت تواجه الموت، لا تزال لا تُظهر أي ندم.
Guards
حراس
Take Shi Feifan to the Imperial Prison
خذ شي فيفان إلى السجن الإمبراطوري
Execution at noon tomorrow
سيتم تنفيذ حكم الإعدام ظهر غدٍ
I bear Heaven's mandate
أنا أحمل تفويض السماء
Shi Feifan disregarded the law
تجاهل شي فيفان القانون
Violated ancient virtue, killed a prince
انتهك فضيلة قديمة، وقتل أميراً
The law cannot tolerate this
لا يمكن للقانون أن يتسامح مع هذا
Now to uphold order and discipline
والآن للحفاظ على النظام والانضباط
Send Shi Feifan to the Imperial Prison
أرسل شي فيفان إلى السجن الإمبراطوري
Await further punishment
انتظر المزيد من العقاب
Announce this to all
أعلنوا هذا للجميع
Pass down the order
قم بتسليم الأمر
Anyone who pleads for Shi Feifan
أي شخص يتوسل من أجل شي فيفان
Will be executed as well
سيتم تنفيذه أيضاً
Shi Feifan
شي فيفان
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
As long as I can be with you
طالما أستطيع أن أكون معك
Even if I eat only husks and greens, I'm not afraid
حتى لو اقتصرت غذائي على قشور الخضار والخضراوات الورقية، فأنا لست خائفاً.
Even if I go to the underworld
حتى لو ذهبت إلى العالم السفلي
I'm willing to go with you
أنا على استعداد للذهاب معك
I once wasted my time
لقد أضعت وقتي ذات مرة
Thought life was nothing special
ظننت أن الحياة ليست مميزة
But right now
لكن الآن
I wish I could live a long life
أتمنى أن أعيش حياة طويلة
Don't worry
لا تقلق
I will get you out for sure
سأخرجك بالتأكيد
Thank you
شكرًا لك
What?
ماذا؟
You've always seen me as a love rival?
هل كنت تراني دائماً كمنافسة في الحب؟
Then you
ثُم أنت
What do you plan to do next?
ما هي خطتك التالية؟
Go somewhere no one knows me
اذهب إلى مكان لا يعرفني فيه أحد
Start over
ابدأ من جديد
Take care of yourself
اعتنِ بنفسك
Please tell Shi Feifan
من فضلك قل شي Feifan
We're even now
نحن متساوون الآن
How hateful I am, truly.
كم أنا بغيض، حقاً.
I wouldn't dare.
لن أجرؤ على ذلك.
You must have already, in your heart,
لا بد أنك تملك بالفعل، في قلبك،
cursed me tens of thousands of times.
لعنني عشرات الآلاف من المرات.
Your Majesty, you are absolutely right.
جلالتك، أنت محق تماماً.
You—
أنت-
Sometimes I truly envy you.
أحياناً أشعر بالغيرة منك حقاً.
You speak your mind when upset.
أنت تعبر عن رأيك بصراحة عندما تكون منزعجاً.
You strike out when unhappy.
تضرب عندما تكون غير سعيد.
No need to weigh or consider.
لا داعي للوزن أو التفكير.
No need to think of pros and cons.
لا داعي للتفكير في الإيجابيات والسلبيات.
I ascended the throne as a child.
اعتليت العرش وأنا طفل.
Prime Minister Lü suppressed me.
قام رئيس الوزراء لو بقمعي.
I wish to be a good emperor loved by the people.
أتمنى أن أكون إمبراطوراً صالحاً يحبه الشعب.
But as a ruler,
لكن كحاكم،
I am not free to act as I wish.
لست حراً في التصرف كما أشاء.
At just twenty-something years old,
في سن العشرينيات فقط،
How can you be so constrained?
كيف يمكن أن تكون مقيداً إلى هذا الحد؟
You hold the highest position in the land.
أنت تشغل أعلى منصب في البلاد.
Loyal subjects support you, the people adore you.
يدعمك رعاياك المخلصون، ويعشقك الشعب.
What could be impossible for you?
ما الذي يمكن أن يكون مستحيلاً بالنسبة لك؟
Life is not always smooth sailing.
الحياة ليست دائماً سهلة.
More often, it is rowing against the current.
في أغلب الأحيان، يكون الأمر أشبه بالتجديف عكس التيار.
If Your Majesty wishes to reach the end faster,
إذا رغبت جلالتكم في الوصول إلى النهاية بشكل أسرع،
I do have a suggestion.
لدي اقتراح.
Your Majesty—
جلالتك—
My father spent his life in battle.
أمضى والدي حياته في المعارك.
His wounds are countless.
جراحه لا تُحصى.
After yesterday's events,
بعد أحداث الأمس،
he exhausted too much of his strength.
لقد استنفد الكثير من قوته.
He fell ill as soon as he returned.
أصيب بالمرض فور عودته.
I humbly ask Your Majesty
أطلب بتواضع من جلالتكم
to allow my father to retire and return home, enjoying his old age.
للسماح لوالدي بالتقاعد والعودة إلى المنزل، والاستمتاع بشيخوخته.
Since Elder Shi is unwell,
بما أن الشيخ شي مريض،
I grant your request.
أوافق على طلبك.
In honor of Elder Shi's loyal service,
تكريماً لخدمة الشيخ شي المخلصة،
I reward him with ten thousand taels of gold.
أكافئه بعشرة آلاف تيل من الذهب.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكراً لك يا صاحب الجلالة.
Last night, my father gave me the Tiger Tally.
أعطاني والدي الليلة الماضية كتاب "إحصاء النمور".
But I believe I lack the ability.
لكنني أعتقد أنني أفتقر إلى القدرة.
I wish to present the Tiger Tally to Your Majesty.
أود أن أقدم لكم إحصاء النمور.
And hope Your Majesty
وأرجو من جلالتكم
will continue to treat the Shi Family Army well.
سنواصل معاملة جيش عائلة شي معاملة حسنة.
It seems the plan must be moved up again.
يبدو أنه يجب تقديم موعد الخطة مرة أخرى.